The story of a nobody who saved everybody.
The Lego Movie is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Phil Lord.
An ordinary Lego mini-figure, mistakenly thought to be the extraordinary MasterBuilder, is
recruited to join a quest to stop an evil Lego tyrant from conquering the universe.
Emmet Brickowski (voice), played by Chris Pratt.
Wyldstyle / Lucy (voice), played by Elizabeth Banks.
Lord Business / President Business / The Man Upstairs, played by Will Ferrell.
Vitruvius (voice), played by Morgan Freeman.
Batman / Bruce Wayne (voice), played by Will Arnett.
Bad Cop / Good Cop / Pa Cop (voice), played by Liam Neeson.
The Lego Movie is a 2014 animated adventure comedy film written
and directed by Phil Lord and Christopher Miller.
Based on the Lego line of construction toys, the film stars the voices of Chris Pratt, Will Ferrell, Elizabeth
Banks, Will Arnett, Nick Offerman, Alison Brie, Charlie Day, Liam Neeson and Morgan Freeman.
The story focuses on Emmet Brickowski (Pratt), an ordinary Lego minifigure who is believed to be "the Special" and is destined to help a
resistance movement stop a tyrannical businessman (Ferrell) from gluing everything in the Lego world into his vision of perfection.
Plans of a feature film based on Lego started in 2008 after a discussion
between producers Dan Lin and Roy Lee before Lin left Warner Bros.
to form his own production company, Lin Pictures.
By August 2009, it was announced that Dan and Kevin
Hageman had begun writing the script.
It was officially green-lit by Warner Bros.
in November 2011 with a planned 2014 release date.
Chris McKay was brought in to co-direct in 2011 with Lord and
Miller, and later became the film's animation supervisor.
The film was inspired by the visual aesthetic and stylistics of
Brickfilms and qualities attributed to Lego Studios sets.
While Lord and Miller wanted to make the film's animation replicate a stop-motion film, everything was done through
computer animation, with the animation rigs following the same articulation limits actual Lego figures have.
Much of the cast signed on to voice the characters in 2012, including Pratt, Ferrell, Banks, Arnett, Freeman and
Brie, while the animation was provided by Animal Logic, which was expected to comprise 80% of the film.
The film was dedicated to Kathleen Fleming, the former director of entertainment
development of the Lego company, who had died in Cancún, Mexico, in April 2013.
The Lego Movie premiered in Los Angeles on February 1, 2014, and was
released theatrically in the United States on February 7.
It became a critical and commercial success, grossing $470.7 million worldwide against its $60–65 million
budget, and received acclaim for its animation, writing, story, humor, score, and voice acting.
The National Board of Review named The Lego Movie
one of the top-ten films of 2014.
It received a nomination for Best Original Song at the 87th
Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
The Lego Movie is the first entry in what became the franchise of the same name, which includes three more films—The
Lego Batman Movie, The Lego Ninjago Movie (both 2017), and The Lego Movie 2: The Second Part (2019).
It has since been recognized as one of the greatest animated films of all time.
The film explores themes of friendship, parent child
relationship, prophecy, superhero, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.